[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b41a", "question": "Which Empire was Cambodia once known as?", "answer": "Khmer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339507", "question": "Who provides the voice for Abe Sapien in the 2004 movie \"Hellboy\"?", "answer": "David Hyde Pierce", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa5658c73aa70ea0b70b2a", "question": "What color do people wear for the New Year in Brazil?", "answer": "White", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b89", "question": "What is the number of thieves that Alibaba had?", "answer": "40", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf6b", "question": "In the game \"Joust\", what animal was your mount?", "answer": "An Ostritch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba71", "question": "Founded in 1924, what department store\u2019s name includes the street of its original New York City address?", "answer": "Saks Fifth Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1a", "question": "Who is Mary Shelley's most famous scientist character?", "answer": "Dr. Frankenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d1", "question": "Angel Falls, the highest waterfall in the world, is located in what country?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b636", "question": "Which salad dressing was named after a play?", "answer": "Green Goddess", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc9e", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Manchette\"?", "answer": "Fencing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab1a55baab681b09292193", "question": "Which Maserati vehicle was designed and built on the Enzo Ferrari chassis?", "answer": "The MC12", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfe159616e6c6d4eba4fb", "question": "What island does the Statue of Liberty stand on?", "answer": "Liberty Island", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388da", "question": "Who was the Greek goddess of marriage and women as well as the queen of heaven?", "answer": "Hera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a0c", "question": "What is the name of the gypsy girl who Quasimodo fell in love with?", "answer": "Esmeralda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb90", "question": "What four-word expression meaning \"everything\" is derived from the three main parts of a musket?", "answer": "Lock, stock and barrel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada7", "question": "How many years did the \"Great Plague of Milan\" last?", "answer": "Two", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81bdbd0de9af39e9d467d", "question": "What was Martin Van Buren nickname?", "answer": "Old Kinderhook", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d4", "question": "In the song where was \"The House of the Rising Sun\" located?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5971e06089261e916c8e09ab", "question": "What US state was \"Steak 'n Shake\" founded in?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c092", "question": "Who invented the Gatling gun?", "answer": "Richard Jordan Gatling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a495", "question": "Which Australian state borders all other mainland states?", "answer": "South Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a0ed20565ad31a57c79d", "question": "Who created the centigrade scale?", "answer": "Anders Celsius", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c8a4f090aac110e416706f", "question": "What fruit are Kriek lambics made with?", "answer": "Cherries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab99b5121a8909e5c332d2a", "question": "Which private investigator tried to find out who framed Roger Rabbit?", "answer": "Eddie Valiant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfce", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"U\"?", "answer": "Uniform", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd3a5ec223966ae8f88c6", "question": "What famous film character says: \"I'm gonna make him an offer he can't refuse\"?", "answer": "Vito Corleone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133942f", "question": "Who directed the 1989 movie \"Dead Poets Society\"?", "answer": "Peter Weir", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c418", "question": "What name is given to the closest star to the Earth?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ca", "question": "Who played the male lead in the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "Cary Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ac", "question": "Blues legend McKinley Morganfield was better known by what name?", "answer": "Muddy Waters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f4c4fa5fdd6dd25324e5", "question": "What country borders Central African Republic to the north?", "answer": "Chad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cd58ae347d002c297e4b7", "question": "What year did James Fenimore Cooper publish the novel \"The Last of the Mohicans\"?", "answer": "1826", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ff", "question": "What was the name of the first human in space?", "answer": "Yuri Gagarin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4d990408b8581f80b092b2", "question": "What month in 2017 did North Korea fire a test missile across the Sea of Japan, prompting international condemnation?", "answer": "February", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062b3dc9d816e292245c1f", "question": "In which Massachusetts town is \"Little Women\" set?", "answer": "Louisa May Alcott\u2019s semi-autobiographical work takes place in Concord, Massachusetts, where she and her three sisters lived.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133911c", "question": "Who wrote the 1910 novel \"Howards End\"?", "answer": "E. M. Forster", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396df", "question": "In which country was Nicole Kidman born?", "answer": "United States", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec86bcec223966ae8f8811", "question": "Who was the first female artist in history to have 4 consecutive singles from one album reach the Top 5 in the Billboard Hot 100?", "answer": "Cyndi Lauper's 1983 classic \"She's So Unusual\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b440", "question": "Who was the 32nd President of the United States?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b120", "question": "What historical figure appeared on the face of the US dollar coins minted from 1979 to 1981, and again in 1999?", "answer": "Susan B. Anthony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338942", "question": "What kind of flowers did Mary Poppins wear in her hair?", "answer": "Daisies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c49d", "question": "Self-rising flour contains what crucial ingredient?", "answer": "Baking powder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b52f", "question": "What plant is rum made from?", "answer": "Sugar cane", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8cc", "question": "Burning potassium has what color flame?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339323", "question": "What game does Beetlejuice play with Lydia to get her to guess his name?", "answer": "Charades", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa61", "question": "What is the capital of the United Arab Emirates?", "answer": "Abu Dhabi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c98", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Stuckeyville, Ohio?", "answer": "Ed", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca9", "question": "What drink is made from fermented honey, yeast and water?", "answer": "Mead", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba37d874c93a3298b213c", "question": "What additional part does someone with Polyorhidism have?", "answer": "Extra testicle(s)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba82", "question": "What was the first American company to manufacture color TV sets in the US?", "answer": "RCA", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab0d", "question": "What is the capital of Greece?", "answer": "Athens", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b573", "question": "What sport is Jenson Button associated with?", "answer": "Motorsport", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e6", "question": "Who played the role of Bobby Donnell on the TV show \"The Practice\"?", "answer": "Dylan McDermott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c692", "question": "A nebula is a large interstellar cloud of what?", "answer": "Dust and gases", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ef", "question": "In what industry did Cornelius Vanderbilt earn his fortune?", "answer": "Railroad", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f0", "question": "What unit of land measurement equals 43,560 square feet?", "answer": "An acre", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c8a50e90aac110e4167070", "question": "What is Homer Simpson\u2019s beer of choice?", "answer": "Duff", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c90d55952800b05cac20f1d", "question": "During what geological time period did the T-Rex roam the Earth?", "answer": "Cretaceous Period", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8ff1101dd7bf43be5e860", "question": "Whose birthday is celebrated on the third Monday in February in the US?", "answer": "President George Washington's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339039", "question": "The opera Aida was commissioned to mark what event?", "answer": "Opening of the Khedivial Opera House", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bedf", "question": "Who won the US Open men's tennis title in 1990 at the age of just 19?", "answer": "Pete Sampras", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6574bae7e414034b5aedb", "question": "Where did Barack Obama teach constitutional law?", "answer": "University of Chicago", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ade", "question": "What author's Jamaican estate was called \"Goldeneye\"?", "answer": "Ian Fleming's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d474acf8e329de4f87789f", "question": "On what date did Margaret Thatcher assume office as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom?", "answer": "May 4, 1979", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a63e20565ad31a57c7d5", "question": "What was the name of the first nuclear-powered aircraft carrier?", "answer": "USS Enterprise CVN-65", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a680", "question": "Which US state shares a border with the Canadian province of New Brunswick?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b148", "question": "Who was the first US President born outside the 13 original states?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln,", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c6e9877e98cb977789c4", "question": "Where can you find the Dragon Blood Tree", "answer": "Yemen", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe377bb0ada16518afdc04b", "question": "After giving up mural painting, Gustav Klimt designed for what industry?", "answer": "Fashion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feddaff6ce05a3942286d8c", "question": "What store in Diagon Alley sells ingredients for potion making?", "answer": "The Apothecary", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c47efbde8045e484669c", "question": "What are the only large cats that roar together as a group?", "answer": "Lions -- Used to mark territories, a pride of lions can be heard from 5 miles away.  Even the young cubs will join in the roaring.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f80301dd7bf43be5e83c", "question": "Cynophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Dogs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec1", "question": "What place was rumored to house aliens in the US?", "answer": "Area 51", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b272", "question": "What Filipino volcano's 1991 eruption produced ten times more ash than Mount Saint Helens had?", "answer": "Mount Pinatubo's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb67445dad637d903c883c", "question": "What country\u2019s land is mostly on an island, although most of its people live on a peninsula across the South China Sea?", "answer": "Malaysia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d30", "question": "What Swedish pop group was anchored by sisters Jenny and Linn Berggren?", "answer": "Ace of Base", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae23", "question": "In which decade did the construction of the Trans-Siberian Railroad commence?", "answer": "1890s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c5049076251badbead1", "question": "The term \"first family\" came into popularity under which U.S. President?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy -- Comedian/Kennedy impressionist Vaughn Meader titled his Grammy-winning 1962 album \"First Family\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cb53bb53d1af658864d7", "question": "In the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", how many drummers are drumming?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c602", "question": "The moons of Uranus are named after characters from the works of what writers?", "answer": "Shakespeare and Alexander Pope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab96a986faa38a764be521", "question": "Despite not being the first company to make a minivan, which company introduced the first successful mass-produced minivan in 1983?", "answer": "Chrysler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d79", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Saga of an American Family\"?", "answer": "Roots", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba29", "question": "What was the original name of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "Liberty Enlightening the World", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c14a", "question": "Sophophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Learning", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f41efa5fdd6dd25324dd", "question": "In the field of psychiatry what term described self-love?", "answer": "Narcissism", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed2", "question": "What is the flower that stands for \"a heart ignorant of love\"?", "answer": "White rosebud", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c792", "question": "Cheetahs are native to what two continents?", "answer": "Africa and Asia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fab", "question": "What peace activist was the emcee at Woodstock?", "answer": "Wavy Gravy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f7c9fe83fe1f2a824c26", "question": "Who was the UK\u2019s second woman Prime Minister?", "answer": "Theresa May", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c270", "question": "What is February's birthstone?", "answer": "Amethyst", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42a", "question": "In what country would you see \"whirling dervishes\"?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe937ff6bd93ce3a4e5f67d", "question": "Herpetophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Reptiles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c26d", "question": "What is a nanominute?", "answer": "One-billionth of a minute", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b83e", "question": "What 2 articles of clothing are tokens in the standard Monopoly game?", "answer": "Shoe and Top Hat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c575", "question": "What name is given to shellfish that cling to the bottom of ships?", "answer": "Barnacles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c6", "question": "Who did agent John Drake work for in \"Secret Agent\"?", "answer": "NATO", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e6", "question": "What name is given to the ancient Christian and Jewish underground burial chambers in and around Rome?", "answer": "Catacombs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c442", "question": "What flowers do florists often refer to as \"mums\"?", "answer": "Chrysanthemums", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6008df93f4f3bc4a292f862c", "question": "What does Passover commemorate?", "answer": "It commemorates how Moses safely led the Jews out of Egypt, where they had spent centuries living in slavery under the Pharaohs.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baa1", "question": "The ghost pepper is cultivated in what country?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d04", "question": "What author's books include \"Call of the Wild\" and \"White Fang\"?", "answer": "Jack London", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf1", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of A Thin Man\"?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d34c2596a59cbdfbd39a", "question": "Which city was the first capital of the United States?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec1", "question": "What is the stage name of rapper Jayceon Taylor?", "answer": "The Game", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d47088f8e329de4f877892", "question": "What is a Winter Banana?", "answer": "A variety of apple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c43c", "question": "What plastic often has its name shortened to PS?", "answer": "Polystyrene", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924f", "question": "What movie's first batch of soap is made out of fat from liposuction clinics?", "answer": "Fight Club's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c884", "question": "What popular computer language shares its name the SI unit of pressure?", "answer": "Pascal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c52", "question": "\"The Tonight Show\" premiered in what year?", "answer": "1954", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd770e347d002c297e4c3", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Diana?", "answer": "Artemis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e5", "question": "What is the study of insects called?", "answer": "Entomology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d3", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Da Vinci Code\"?", "answer": "Dan Brown", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2fd", "question": "Before being surpassed, what was the world's tallest building fort just a few months in 1930?", "answer": "The Chrysler Building", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b85b", "question": "What spirit is mixed with ginger beer and lime to make a Moscow Mule?", "answer": "Vodka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338906", "question": "Who wrote the music for the stage version of \"Billy Elliot\"?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b36ae662d71a53650fdf", "question": "Which famous composer continued working as he lost his hearing?", "answer": "Ludwig van Beethoven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fbae7150738315b1fb74e25", "question": "What is the sum of the angles of a triangle?", "answer": "180 degrees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60121a1963c99d48cd169b00", "question": "What kind of nut is used to make marzipan?", "answer": "Almond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339273", "question": "In season 13 of the Big Brother show, half of this duo was the first eliminated and the other half remained?", "answer": "Keith and Porsche", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cacd", "question": "What does a heliologist study?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd667e3a5bfecdd737e086d", "question": "How old did the oldest recorded person live to be?", "answer": "122-years-old", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a19", "question": "What nationality was Vincent van Gogh?", "answer": "Dutch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fc2f1a7cee580c7f8fd1e51", "question": "Who said, \"You only live once, but if you do it right, once is good enough.\"?", "answer": "Mae West", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339358", "question": "What was Tony's last name on the TV show \"Who's the Boss\"?", "answer": "Micelli", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f6f75a9e54d890926f6d1", "question": "What was the capital of Michigan before Lansing?", "answer": "Detroit -- Due to Detroit's proximity to Canada, a perceived threat at the time, Lansing became the state's capital in 1847.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a7f51a6f5f79087132fb3d", "question": "What do British people call zucchini?", "answer": "Courgette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b7cfe662d71a53651018", "question": "In which city is the Prado Art Gallery?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded33fea2747c8aff16d46", "question": "What type of a clothing item is a \"Sam Browne\"?", "answer": "A belt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdfbefc003d27d341092bd3", "question": "How many Brazilian states are there?", "answer": "26", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a46a", "question": "What is known as the Old Lady Of Threadneedle Street?", "answer": "The Bank of England", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b127", "question": "In what city was the UN charter signed?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f95aea455722f97b22684d5", "question": "Which Star Wars character is the first to be partially named after director George Lucas\u2019 son?", "answer": "Dexter Jettster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a764", "question": "What is the only country which borders the Black Sea and the Caspian  Sea?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bbc92f460f0007efaba0e59", "question": "What is the name of Roy Rogers' horse?", "answer": "Trigger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc0", "question": "In Greek Mythology, what hung from an oak tree in the grove of Ares in Colchis, guarded by a dragon?", "answer": "The Golden Fleece", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8bd", "question": "What is the more common name for Umbilicus?", "answer": "Belly button", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad57", "question": "Queen Mary of England made her reputation by trying to rid her country of what segment of the population?", "answer": "Protestants", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c467", "question": "What is the proper term for a young eel?", "answer": "An elver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c6d", "question": "Who directed the 1983 sequel to the movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "Sylvester Stallone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b885", "question": "In bowling, what would your score be if you bowled 11 strikes and a 6?", "answer": "296", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339261", "question": "Who had the fingers on his left hand glued together to make his disability look more real in the movie \"The Usual Suspects\"?", "answer": "Kevin Spacey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8d4a72b42d4a3561a9efb", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what nickname did Katchoo go by when working in L.A. as an escort?", "answer": "Baby June", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0d", "question": " What month does the summer solstice occur in the northern hemisphere?", "answer": "June", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339132", "question": "What year was the second instalment of \"The Faerie Queene\" epic poem published?", "answer": "1596", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3fd", "question": "What is the only National Park located in Michigan?", "answer": "Isle Royale National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e482fe83fe1f2a824bb5", "question": "In the last six months of the war, what was the U.S. strategy for winning the conflict with Japan?", "answer": "Break the Japanese will with massive bombing raids on Japanese cities", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938f", "question": "What role did James Dean play in the movie \"Rebel Without a Cause\"?", "answer": "Jim Stark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5971dd5089261e916c8e099d", "question": "At what wind speed does a tropical storm become a hurricane?", "answer": "74mph (119km/hr)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba9", "question": "Which city is served by Schwechat airport?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ae", "question": "In what city would you find Gorky Park?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e5f112ed274615ecf514538", "question": "What is the name of Olive Oyl\u2019s father?", "answer": "Cole Oyl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6002413e4be4723ccac22173", "question": "Sydney Carton is the central character in what Charles Dickens novel?", "answer": "\"A Tale of Two Cities\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff51be6ff04d658268c9312", "question": "Who was the husband of the female Judge Deborah in the Bible?", "answer": "Lapidoth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4dd5d06d333868d34d701", "question": "In which concentration camp did Anne Frank die?", "answer": "Bergen-Belsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5bde6ce05a3942286e19", "question": "The Jeffersons\" was a spinoff of what show?", "answer": "\"All in the Family\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e68106d333868d34d733", "question": "What was Joseph Stalin's nationality?", "answer": "Georgian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd1", "question": "Who was the beautiful youth loved by the Greek goddess Aphrodite?", "answer": "Adonis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ca3dbb44f0f6af5b06663e", "question": "What is the capital of Andorra?", "answer": "Andorra la Vella", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfbb", "question": "March, April and May are the only months that have what?", "answer": "Anagrams - Charm, Ripal, Yam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c07a", "question": "Pupaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Puppets", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7ceb2877e98cb97778a45", "question": "What country's flag features the phrase \"Order and Progress\"?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a195", "question": "\"Love Bites\" was the only song to reach number one on the Billboard Hot 100 for which rock band?", "answer": "Def Leppard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600242004be4723ccac22180", "question": "Which Irish poet, born in 1865, was instrumental in the founding of the Abbey Theatre in Dublin?", "answer": "William Butler Yeats", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ec3f08d98002fdd633b9", "question": "What character, created by A. A. Milne, loves watercress?", "answer": "Roo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7a", "question": "What Italian phrase for \"from the beginning\" is used in music notation to indicate a repeated passage?", "answer": "Da capo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339891", "question": "Who played Clark Kent in the first \"Superman\" movie in 1978?", "answer": "Christopher Reeve", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b544", "question": "What does Pinocchio in Italian mean?", "answer": "Pine eyes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c180", "question": "What is the more common name of Sildenafil Citrate?", "answer": "Viagra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e8a66eb9a45431f553a9cd0", "question": "Who played Tim in the cult U.K. sitcom \"Spaced\"?", "answer": "Simon Pegg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c757", "question": "What is the opposite of nocturnal?", "answer": "Diurnal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b2f", "question": "Choreographer and actor Chris Judd was what actress and singer's second husband?", "answer": "Jennifer Lopez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b711", "question": "What contribution to Christmas is John Calcott Horsely credited with?", "answer": "The first mass-produced Christmas card", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e242fe83fe1f2a824b9d", "question": "On which region of the Soviet Union did Hitler place the highest priority?", "answer": "Ukraine and southern Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa1d", "question": "Jefferson City is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7ca1f877e98cb97778a02", "question": "Which peninsula is shared by Portugal and Spain?", "answer": "Iberian peninsula", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c02e", "question": "Who is Reginald Kenneth Dwight otherwise known as?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e37", "question": "Who plays drums on the Beatles track \"Back in the U.S.S.R.\"?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c9", "question": "What was Audrey Hepburn's real last name?", "answer": "Ruston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d7", "question": "What fruit is \"Citrus grandis\"?", "answer": "Pomelo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba5f", "question": "In what Missouri town did Mark Twain grow up?", "answer": "Hannibal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133927a", "question": "Which member of the Quack Pack in season 14 of the TV show \"Big Brother\" did not make it to the final?", "answer": "Britney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008d9ccf842fa4c4ba96ab", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Oedipus marry?", "answer": "Jocasta, his mother", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5af25b0db63e5727cf5a4858", "question": "Which Canadian singer performed the song \"(Everything I Do) I Do It for You\"?", "answer": "Bryan Adams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b0", "question": "Which European country is divided into areas called Cantons?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339786", "question": "Who was the lead singer of \"The Crickets\"?", "answer": "Buddy Holly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca62", "question": "The ore bauxite is the chief commercial source of which element?", "answer": "Aluminium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4b4549076251badbeac1", "question": "Who was the first female U.S. Attorney General?", "answer": "Janet Reno -- She served as the attorney general for President Bill Clinton's entire presidency.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe37a840ada16518afdc05a", "question": "Who was the leader of China during World War II?", "answer": "Chiang Kai-shek", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a83a", "question": "What US city's nicknames include \"The Crescent City\" and \"The City that Care Forgot\"?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0f9", "question": "Which US amendment to the Constitution limits the president to two terms?", "answer": "22nd", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e801f2de59ea584496fe94", "question": "In which state would you find the \"House of the Seven Gables\"?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae73", "question": "What started in 1849 when gold was discovered at Sutter's Mill?", "answer": "The California Gold Rush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05a", "question": "In what year did Richard Nixon resign as President of the US?", "answer": "1974", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e6", "question": "In what city is Gonzaga University located?", "answer": "Spokane, Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3d5", "question": "A male swan is called a what?", "answer": "Cob", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af6", "question": "What TV science guy wore a red polka-dot bow tie on the box of his \"Way Cool Game of Science\" CD-ROM?", "answer": "Bill Nye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf2c", "question": "How many balls are on a pool table at the start of a game?", "answer": "16", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600398b657a0e35c43f8389d", "question": "James McNeill Whistler's Arrangement in Grey and Black No.1 is better known by what other name?", "answer": "Whistler's Mother\u00a0-- It is exhibited in the Mus\u00e9e d'Orsay in Paris, having been bought by the French state in 1891.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c1", "question": "What CEO bounced back after being fired by Henry Ford II in 1978?", "answer": "Lee Iacocca", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc9", "question": "Who was sent to the electric chair on the testimony of her brother David Greenglass?", "answer": "Ethel Rosenberg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c182", "question": "What is the name for the number 1 followed by 100 zeros?", "answer": "Googol", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ae", "question": "Io orbits what planet of the solar system?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c70", "question": "What was H.G. Wells' first novel?", "answer": "The Time Machine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e84", "question": "What power does \"The Monkey's Paw\" possess in the 1902 short story?", "answer": "It grants three wishes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc5cbec223966ae8f8883", "question": "Bruce Willis played a convict turned time traveler in what 1995 movie?", "answer": "\"12 Monkeys\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e5", "question": "Who founded eBay in 1995?", "answer": "Pierre Omidyar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e147eb06ca6dac04a20ca51", "question": "Mogadishu is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Somalia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339110", "question": "In which play by Tennessee Williams would you encounter the character \"Big Daddy\"?", "answer": "Cat on a Hot Tin Roof", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca75", "question": "How many feet are there in a fathom?", "answer": "6", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af32", "question": "What war was fought from 1754 to 1763?", "answer": "The Seven Year's War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600a2704e958e8c9f3127313", "question": "Where did the Mayflower land in New England in 1620?", "answer": "Cape Cod - The Mayflower sailed from England to the \u201cNew World,\u201d landing in Plymouth Harbor along the shores of Cape Cod.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b323514bf195a31e15d73ab", "question": "Sergey Bubka has set a world record in which field event over 30 times?", "answer": "Pole Vault", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d4172596a59cbdfbd3a1", "question": "What part of the computer does \"QWERTY\" refer to?", "answer": "Keyboard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fffa77173838c5c8a417f38", "question": "What are people who love eating ice called?", "answer": "Pagophagiacs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8aa6b01dd7bf43be5e75a", "question": "What\u2019s another name for a footrest?", "answer": "Ottoman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fc", "question": "Which word, taken from the French, translates literally as \"rotten pot\"?", "answer": "Potpourri", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a525", "question": "The Hollywood Walk of Fame is located along what street?", "answer": "Hollywood Boulevard", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e97a9ebfabb9c85d8a965", "question": "Which popular beverage's name is German for \"storeroom\"?", "answer": "Lager", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab2", "question": "Karakul, Dorset, Urial, and Jacob are types of what?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f7161a9e54d890926f6de", "question": "What is the capital city of Paraguay?", "answer": "Asuncion", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f9c", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7e97db24f84e0b9f9ffce", "question": "What precious metal did alchemists call \"luna\"?", "answer": "Silver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a44", "question": "What author created the characters Ponyboy and Sodapop?", "answer": "S.E. Hinton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59c1ceb47bd84c0ea43ad43a", "question": "Who is Thomas John Woodward better known as?", "answer": "Tom Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a344", "question": "Anna Faris plays Cindy Campbell in what horror movie spoof?", "answer": "Scary Movie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db77020ab2c8f322317fea", "question": "Who played Norman Bates in the 1998 film \"Psycho\"?", "answer": "Vince Vaughn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339915", "question": "In the movie \"Austin Powers in Goldmember\", what country is Goldmember from?", "answer": "Holland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc6", "question": "What popular soft drink claims to contain 23 flavors?", "answer": "Dr. Pepper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb87", "question": "What TV evangelist was sent to prison for defrauding followers of his PTL Ministry out of $158 million?", "answer": "Jim Bakker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab97ef86faa38a764be52c", "question": "How many cars had to be stolen in the 2000 film remake of \"Gone in 60 Seconds\"?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd95", "question": "What was the pseudonym of famous cross-dresser Amandine-Aurore-Lucile Dupin?", "answer": "George Sand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea49f5ff048f679a45abbe", "question": "A buck, or male deer, is also called a what?", "answer": "Stag", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f5664733a95c66dc4fe761", "question": "In which film did Orson Welles play the role of Harry Lime?", "answer": "The Third Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8efe901dd7bf43be5e7f6", "question": "What is the official name for a blob of toothpaste on a toothbrush?", "answer": "Nurdle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc1ed6ce05a3942286f18", "question": "What country is the setting for the film \"The Deep\"?", "answer": "Bermuda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c67c", "question": "Bruxism is a medical term for when a person does what?", "answer": "Grinds their teeth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6aa", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for the element Magnesium on the periodic table?", "answer": "Mg", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe522ae1bf59ab7d2e380e9", "question": "\"100% Squeezed Sunshine\" has been which company's ad slogan?", "answer": "Tropicana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c5dafbde8045e48466b1", "question": "An \"unkindness\" refers to a group of what animal?", "answer": "Ravens -- They have a bad reputation, and have been considered bad omens for centuries.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e3", "question": "What does an anemometer measure?", "answer": "Wind speed", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a5f", "question": "On what thoroughfare does the Muffin Man live?", "answer": "Drury Lane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6002449b4be4723ccac221a6", "question": "What artist is known for having painted the Moulin Rouge?", "answer": "Henri de Toulouse-Lautrec produced a collection of provocative images of the decadent life of 19th century Paris.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f8", "question": "How many natural satellites does Jupiter have?", "answer": "79", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b48e649076251badbeaa8", "question": "Who was the first American woman in space?", "answer": "Sally Ride -- One of six women selected for NASA Astronaut Group 8, she traveled on Space Shuttle Challenger's STS-7 mission.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394da", "question": "What was Shari Lewis' hand puppet called?", "answer": "Lamb Chop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9026301dd7bf43be5e869", "question": "What is difference between Cognac and brandy?", "answer": "Cognac is a brandy only produced in Cognac, France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba46b874c93a3298b2144", "question": "What does the word \"economy\" mean in Ancient Greek?", "answer": "Household management", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8fb6501dd7bf43be5e851", "question": "What kind of liquor is Cognac?", "answer": "Brandy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe4", "question": "What colony was established by the passengers of the Mayflower?", "answer": "Plymouth Colony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97e", "question": "What would you add to a Welsh Rarebit to make a Buck Rarebit?", "answer": "Poached Egg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a6", "question": "Zoologist Dian Fossey dedicated her life to the study of what animals?", "answer": "Gorillas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c65f", "question": "What fruit comes in the Muscat or Scuppernong variety?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aacc", "question": "What city is the capital of the US state of Kansas?", "answer": "Topeka", "category": "geography"}]